[Music]
focus
innovate enable
[Music]
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age
risk management practitioners
ladies and gentlemen it is a pleasure to
welcome you all to the seventh edition
of the icici lumbar general insurance
and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards over the
last six years these awards
have become the most coveted platform to
recognize
and celebrate the best risk management
teams
and initiatives which are innovative
path defining and yet
grounded in a strong base of risk
management
fundamentals as we hold the first ever
virtual edition
of this prestigious awards show in the
backdrop
of the ongoing pandemic there is no
escaping the fact that kovit 19 has
demonstrated that risk is not a
well-behaved house guest
predicting the unpredictable dealing
with risk
and uncertainty it has always been a key
mantra
in the risk management industry and this
holds true today as well
as we all continue to recover from the
impact of covet 19.
the focus is on enhancing the resilience
of our economies
and societies this evening we recognize
and celebrate
the risk managers of tomorrow who have
shown
great foresight and a dynamic approach
to upgrade
and reposition risk management in their
organizations
this year and now to set the ball
rolling i'd like to invite cnbc tv 18's
executive editor lata venkatesh
to deliver the welcome address over to
you
thank you very much gotham uh first up
dr ram charan the management guru
bhargav das gupta of
icici lombard jurors award winners
and the creme de la creme of india's
legal and financial
mind space on behalf of cnbc tv 18 on
on my own behalf and our co-sponsors i
say
lombard i once again welcome all of you
to the seventh edition
of the india risk management awards cnbc
tv 18 actually
partners with many entities to recognize
excellence in various areas
so we have business awards through the
year but the risk management award
is by far the most demanding most
thoroughly analyzing and hence a
personal favorite for me
the winners today have been picked after
a very trying and thorough process
and that we have been able to get
all of you award winners on one platform
makes this day very special thank you
very much and many congratulations
just this one sir to be able to see all
and congratulate you all
i was hoping that this would be an
on-site
event and not a virtual event but
nevertheless i'm
looking forward to enjoying this evening
thank you very much
and thank you for that love and that
sets the tone of the evening in fact and
now
i would like to invite the man who has
staunchly supported these awards for
all of its six editions bhargav dasgupta
managing director
and ceo icici lombard general insurance
to deliver
the keynote address over to you sir
uh thank you and uh and a warm welcome
to all of you from
um you know from ics lombard and from uh
me personally
to the seventh edition of india risk
management awards
now in the previous episodes of this
platform we have been
deliberating the role and the importance
of risk management
and how india incorporated needs to
adapt to it realistically
and over the years we've always had this
big debate about
you know what should we focus on is it
risk or is it you know growth
and is it complementary is it you know
is it uh at uh
odds with each other i think the
experience that in the world has gone
through in the last
you know 10 months unfortunately has
taught us that risk management is core
to
survival and in a extremely volatile and
uncertain world that we live in
uh it is uh a foundation for success
it's not something that you do
also it's something that you build your
you know strategy
on a foundation of at isis and ombud
our approach has been uh moving away
from just being a risk transfer partner
which is what traditional insurers do
but to be a
more of a holistic risk management
partner so we work with corporates to
actually analyze risk and partner with
them to reduce this risk
and as a course of that discussion when
we continuously engage with corporate
firms
to understand their needs uh and
accordingly empower them with relevant
risk management solutions we saw
one gap that was clearly emerging
diverse
organizations across size scale you know
the industry they grapple with
challenges
where you know such as difficulty in
quantifying the risk
that they're exposed to as also
benchmarking
and effectively gauging uh where they
are in terms of risk preparedness
in comparison with with the others so
given this deliberation one of the
things that we
uh you know one of the insights that we
got uh you know helped us
in crafting something that we believe is
truly first of its kind one of its kind
in india
uh based on our discussion with some of
you uh you know including
some of the experts we believe that even
across the world
an index like this that we are about to
launch today doesn't exist
so you know i'm personally very happy to
announce the launch of this
index we call it ics in lombard
corporate india risk index
it's an index which is unified it's
comprehensive
it's quantifiable it measures
risks across 32 different parameters it
buckets these into then
two specific areas again providing
quantitative
scores for each one for the level of
risk that a firm is exposed to
and second the extent to which the
organization is prepared
in case the risks were to strike so in a
sense we are
you know giving them a uh giving the
organization corporates a
clear tool to establish and understand
where they are
in terms of the risk and where to stand
in terms of preparedness to address the
risk
you know at the end let me congratulate
all the winners of this event you know
we'll continue this tradition of
uh celebrating india's best best risk
managers
we seek lots of awards in you know many
other areas
but risk management something that we
felt in the past was
relatively under appreciated and under
awarded
and that's what we are trying to change
thank you once again for joining us
today and wish you a great evening ahead
thank you well we have a special av
lined up on the on the corporate risk
index the icici
lombard general insurance risk index so
let's take a quick look at that
for all of your benefit i see asia
lombard presents
forward india risk index
all right i'd like to invite uh global
president and managing partner of the
frost and sullivan uh
arub zucci to throw more light on the
just lawn icici lombard corporate india
risk index over to you if you talk to
people in the industry it is very clear
that many of the people are still
struggling with this do not fully
understand what it means
and despite having been educated a lot
still do not
have a full comprehensive understanding
of how risk
factors have to be understood and how do
you manage
risk in the in in the business and so
when we talk to
all the cxos as well as the risk
officers
in the business one thing that we find
is that
most of them have very different
definitions of risk whether it is scale
measurement techniques it is very very
different
and that's one of the reasons why
oftentimes people simply don't
put all of these things together so
there is no skill that exists today
that is standardized across sectors and
cannot be considered
unified at all and that's where we spend
a lot of time working together
and building a very comprehensive index
so if you look at how the risk
frameworks work
today the typical risk models measure
probability
and impact but we have taken a
completely different approach
where we measure the firm's exposure and
its ability to manage risk
and which is a lot more relevant in
today's context for business continuity
and more importantly top line and
evident margin growth
so risk index as you can see is a
measure of how well you are being able
to manage the risks you are exposed to
but more importantly how do you navigate
that fine line between risk being an
opportunity
or a threat to your business and that's
why this balance
makes it very very important so what
we've done is actually
looked at you know
leveraging our our standard methodology
we looked at well-established advisory
best practices
and we have combined it with the
principle of lean and six sigma
to create a comprehensive risk matrix
that covers
all aspects of the indian corporate risk
exposure
and we've covered it around 15 sectors
ranging from new age industries to
multinationals
to mncs and of course medium and small
enterprises as well
and obviously this is just the start we
expect that this will continue and will
build
on what we have put together and so
based on that
we have come up with the ic ic lombard
corporate india risk index
and so the the point here is it is it is
a very different scale and it does not
say that
higher is better or lower is better so
for example
if you have a score of 50 to 60 it tells
you that you know your risk very well
and that you are being able to adjust
and manage these risks
better likewise a score of 60 to 80
tells you that you have done some smart
moves you made some smart decisions
and you prepared yourself for the future
and so
based on that what we've done is come up
with
the corporate india risk index
obviously it's a very superior risk
index and industries like the healthcare
bfsi media telecom and i.t and its
typically form the part of this
high risk index in the country and they
of course have high exposure but they
have also done very well in risk
management
but the real economy sectors like the
metals or more
manufacturing uh have have managed the
risk really well overall but not to the
level that we would expect
and the new age hospitality and
logistics sectors have had
have had high intrinsic risk exposure
which are being
to some extent handled suboptimally
indeed thank you so much uh mr zhutri
and as they say let there be light
but before we continue may i request
that we play the special video on the
icici lombard corporate india risk index
for the viewers
in today's world uncertainty is the norm
risk affects everyone
from individuals to companies
[Music]
to countries
in business every sector faces varied
risks
like changes in market conditions
cyber risk
natural hazard risk is widespread
but is there a yardstick to measure it
so that it can be managed better
there are indices to measure various
metrics like air quality
average rainfall the magnitude of an
earthquake
and even the distance to stars
however measuring to what extent an
organization is exposed to
and prepared to manage risk is a
challenging task
presenting icici lombard corporate india
risk index one of its kind
comprehensive and standardized corporate
risk index
so how is the company's risk index
calculated
let's take a look at company x for
instance
32 different risk parameters are
measured through a scientific process
these are segregated into risk exposure
and risk management the parameters are
then used to understand the quantum of
risk being faced by the company
and its level of preparedness to face
these risks
using a well thought through logic these
parameters are used to arrive
at a risco for the company with clear
actionable areas
various companies would be in different
categories on the risk index scale
here's where company x falls on the
corporate risk index scale
[Music]
a score of 60 suggests that company x
can optimally manage
the risk it is currently exposed to
however
managing elements like competitive risk
emerging risk
effectively will boost company x score
this can put it in the superior risk
management category
corporate india risk index is a key
metric for companies
looking to manage risk icici lombard
corporate india risk index intelligence
partner
frost and sullivan
icier lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
[Music]
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
well it's time now for a special segment
and for that
it's over to you lata well thank you
very much uh
gotham to all of you uh if you remember
in the past in the previous awards we
have normally
invited uh economists you know kenneth
rogoff uh
uh reinhardt
merely because we thought that there are
risks in the economy
but corvette changed our thinking for
covet-affected companies
we thought one thing the doctor would
order is a management guru
like dr ramcharan you know dr charon is
known
for many things but the most important
attribute
is his ability to give ceos and
boards practical real-world actionable
solutions
the kind of advice you can actually use
uh monday morning
dr i welcome you to deliver your special
address
i assure you this is the moment we have
been waiting for
all your sir thank you very much
i'm humbled my mission in life
is to write to talk to deliver
hopefully useful to the practitioners
i will be brief i will try to the point
i congratulate the icici lombard
and the ceo arup from foster sullivan
to create this corporate risk
index it's timely
it's innovative and it is indispensable
on the boards i serve seven of them
across the globe
risk is now at the board level
the second largest
funds largest is the
the the one blackrock second
is the vanguard the chairman of vanguard
is just finishing up his research and a
book
it's called tsr talent
strategy and risk if these three are
integrated
if these three inputs are correct
against the environment and competition
you will have tsr total
shareholder return
this will come out sometime in october
and as i mentioned this the intent
of this index as
bhagavad-gita put it and i totally agree
to improve performance no strategies
without risk
no business without no business model
so it's at the center of choice of
strategy
choice of business model choice of
resource allocation
so our job as risk people is to have
this at the center
in the decisions that the board makes
the ceo and the exo team makes in
resource allocations
in behaviors if you are looking at esg
it is going to be affecting behaviors at
the plant level
if you're looking at cyber it's one of
the behaviors
of the people using all that
the the data and how they use the
devices
this balance is a central part it's
innovative it's new
and just put these things together now
the thing i want to mention
that it is not defensive many people
take risk
as a defensive risk as i think
the the ceo president sullivan put it
it's also an opportunity and that is we
can now quantify
the return on risk it comes
this way it's well known in the
financial side
if your risk balance and opportunity and
exposure is right
and it is balanced with your profit
opportunity
over time it will have an impact on your
sector
what funds are coming what firms are not
coming
it will an effect on your company within
the sector
that will affect the price earning ratio
so the market value
change is the return so
the key thing to watch is that
our own people need to demonstrate
that we can earn cost of capital the
more
we can demonstrate cost of capital the
more confidence
we build of course it has to have risk
premium
more fdi will come china's is a 250
billion a year for a long time
we too can do it but the first part is
execution
second the government has to pose
attention
that we have accountability and earning
cost of capital
we have not done so in telecom we have
not done so in power plant
we have not done so airlines and so when
i sit
on the other side of the table where the
funds are coming
the question is the country risk now
that country risk
and the sectors are not able to run cost
of capital
that's coming in by the indians because
our
indian ceos are very good we have
in largest companies in the world run by
indian ceos
they're algorithmic ones i am
interacting now with 100 million dollar
companies in india
200 million dollar companies these are
superb entrepreneurs
they're superb business people they need
help in scaling up
so we need to have this in mind and our
bright future is very bright
thank you
[Music]
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age
risk management practitioners
ladies and gentlemen let's begin the
highlight of the events proceedings the
seventh edition
of the india risk management awards now
these awards
recognize those organizations and teams
that have significantly added
to the understanding and practice of
risk management
judged by an independent panel of
experts for
exceptional performance the awards
provide an opportunity
for organizations and individuals to
showcase
their best products projects and people
in this edition we feature both the
large cap and the mid cap segments
the mid cap category is relatively new
and this is its second edition
in fact this is the first time that a
separate jury
has been constituted for mid cap
companies
the idea behind this new category is to
recognize
and award risk management efforts of
growing companies
in india over the next half an hour we
will be
celebrating and recognizing those
organizations that have created
and adopted world-class risk management
practices
let's begin with the first set of awards
in the large cap category
well good risk management is about being
alert
implementing the right controls and
taking swift
action to mitigate risk during a crisis
our first category of this evening
is masters of risk in risk governance
the winner of this award is one of the
largest telecom tower companies
in the world it has a network of over 1
lakh and 75 000
and a nationwide presence covering all
22 telecom circles
and the name of our first winner of the
evening
is
indus towers limited formerly bharti
infratel limited
first of all i would like to thank icici
lombard
and cnbc tv 18 for awarding
in this tower limited formerly bharati
and protel limited
with the masters of risk awards for the
current year
this gives us a great motivation and
also
this award is for all the people who
have been behind
building such a great uh and such a
strong
framework for the company all the
stakeholders who have helped us
in achieving great targets over the
years
that's commendable that their
performance i stand over here
receiving this award on behalf of the
company
[Applause]
cyber security issues are becoming more
alarming and
cyber crime has surged during the covet
19 pandemic
repercussions from an attack can lead to
grave impacts on business objectives
and create major disruptions the next
category of the india risk management
awards 2021
is masters of risk in cyber security
well the nominations were judged based
on incident management framework
key initiatives to enhance cyber
security risk framework
board involvement and use of tools and
technology
to enhance cyber security and
the winner is
tata consultancy services limited
tc is quite honored by this recognition
at tcs cyber security
is a key component in all our practices
and hence
on behalf of tcs i would like to thank
jury for looking at our submission and
identifying us
as winners this time i'd also like to
thank ics lombard and cnbc tv 18
for such a great initiative very very
nice organizations like us
[Applause]
business continuity management is a
crucial subset
of risk management next up is the
category of
masters of risk in business continuity
well the award was given on the basis of
parameters such as an
overall maturity of business continuity
management program
scenario testing of disaster recovery
plan
business impact analysis and adoption of
tools and technologies congratulations
to the winner
genpak limited we are extremely pleased
as jenpack to be a winner of the india
risk management award any recognition
that comes from a third party after
evaluation
always helps us to believe that we are
on the right path and do better i'd like
to take this opportunity also to
thank icici lombard and cnbc tv 18
and all the members of the jury who went
through a very thorough process to check
our inputs as well as our readiness to
win this award
[Applause]
[Music]
the supply chain disruptions due to the
lockdown
during the pandemic have altered the
logistics sector
our next category this evening is
masters of
risk in logistics risk management
and the winner of this category is one
of the leading logistics company in the
world
a big congratulations to the exceptional
risk management team
off
blue dart express limited firstly i
would like to thank cnbc icici
bombard as well as the jury members for
considering bloodart for this award
this award is a testimony to all the
blue rutters
all the frontliners our truck drivers
the hub operators
our outsourced service partners as well
as the aviation team
each one work through the situation to
ensure reliability and resilience of
[Applause]
all right let's take a look at the next
category of the india
risk management awards 2021 masters of
risk
in sustainability
well the winner was decided on
parameters such as adoption of
sustainability framework
and compliance with sustainability
framework
with excellent oversight implementation
and stakeholder engagement
the winner is
tata consultancy services limited we are
very pleased
and privileged to receive this award
in tcs we have incorporated
sustainability
as a part of our risk assessment and
risk management process
uh since the past few years now
uh we would like to thank the cnbc tv18
and icsa lombard for instituting these
awards
which will i think add a great value to
the entire
enterprise risk management
focus in the organization
our next set of awards are from the
industry category
starting with masters of risk in it
and it-enabled services
and the winner of this award category
this year
is
cognizant technology solutions it gives
me immense pleasure
and i'm honored to accept the india risk
management awards for the second time on
behalf of my team
and the organization i would like to
thank cnbc tv 18
and icici lombard and members of the
jury for institutionalizing this award
to recognize
excellence in the field of risk
management
[Applause]
moving on to our next award category
this evening masters of risk
in metals and mining
and the winner in this category is
tata steel limited india i would like to
thank the jury
of the india risk management awards uh
icsa numbered
and cnbc for bestowing this recognition
on tata steel
in the methods and mining category this
is a
very credible award for many years now
in its seventh edition
and as a company we have worked on our
risk management systems
and processes and governance over these
years and
it really feels wonderful to be
recognized
by such a forum
[Applause]
once again many congratulations to the
tata group on their multiple wins this
evening
our next category for the evening is
masters of risk
in telecom
and the winner of the award is
reliance geo infocom limited
i'm extremely honored to receive such an
important award
cnbc india risk management award for
2021 for the second year in a row
for the telecom sector i am extremely
grateful
for the recognition received for the
work by the
risk management team award is a
testimonial of
the language leadership division
and faith and hard work putting by the
risk team of jio
[Applause]
all right let's take a look at our next
category this evening masters of risk
in fmcg
and the winner in this category is
tata consumer products limited tata
consumer products is excited to win for
the second time the india risk
management award
it means a lot for us to be recognized
for the good work that we have done
in building a culture of risk in the
organization my thanks to cnbc and to
ics
lombard for giving us this award
[Applause]
[Music]
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
moving on to the next category of the
india risk management awards 2021
masters of risk in pharma and healthcare
and the winner of this award is a
company that has recently received
certification for
international sustainability rating
system the eighth
edition from dnvgl a global service
provider
for managing risk and helping customers
to safely
and responsibly improve their business
performance
the winner i am referring to is
lupin limited we are very happy
to receive this prestigious india
risk management award and i think the
second time we are receiving
this award we are thankful to ica
lombard
and cnbc for pharma industry
the management of the risk is very very
important
and over the years we have been taking
various steps
various measures activities to take care
of the various risks in all the segments
of the business
and this evolved is the true recognition
of
the various measures of various efforts
with the looping has taken
over the years
[Applause]
on to the next category of the india
risk management awards 2021
masters of risk in real estate
and the winner of this category is one
of india's
most trusted real estate brands i'm
talking about
goldridge properties limited this award
is a great testament to the good work
our teams at goodwill properties have
been doing
risk management when you think about it
from the perspective of a real estate
developer
where we're typically managing dozens of
projects in different parts of the
country with a lot of
constantly changing dynamics we really
do see risk management as very central
to
business it's not something that happens
alongside business it is something
that is inherent to what we do so i
think it's
you know very gratifying to us to
receive this recognition from cnbc
um it will certainly help as we continue
to make this call
to our you know practices as a company
it will certainly help inspire and drive
the team to continue to do better
[Applause]
next award for the evening is for
masters of risk in
risk technology
the focus in this category was on
features and functionalities
of technology scalability and security
policy
many congratulations to
tata steel limited india i would like to
thank the jury of the indian risk
management awards
cnbc tv18 and icici lombard for
recognizing tata steel
as masters of this technology
in this category and as you know that
technology plays a very important role
in
risk management and data steel has been
working relentlessly
in this area to use technology as an
enabler
for more effective risk management
[Applause]
our second last award in this category
is masters of risk in
travel and leisure
a big congratulations to the winning
team off
thomas cook india limited we at thomas
cook india limited
are very happy and excited to receive
the india's
risk management award under travel and
leisure segment
this is the fourth time that thomas book
india group is winning this award
and this actually reiterates the
sustainable measures
that we have put over this years
consistently at thomas okay
[Applause]
limited
last award in the large cap category is
a special jury citation for logistics
risk management
and the winner of this special jewry
citation award
is
thermax limited hermac is well respected
global project management organization
and this award will keep thermax
and india into the bigger business
relationship
map and this award means a lot to
thermax because
india is recognized as the risk
evaluating and mitigating company and
this award
will keep thermax and indian companies
at high level
into the global map
[Applause]
and with that we wrap up the large cap
category
a big congratulations to all the winners
once again
the nominees in the mid cap were judged
on parameters such as
policies and formal practices laid out
for risk management
documented operating manuals for key
processes
use of it tools and extent of technology
leverage so
let's get to it the first award is for
masters of risk
in i.t and it-enabled services in the
mid-cap category
and the winner of this category is one
of india's leading healthcare i.t
solutions provider
and that is
monorama info solutions private limited
it gives me immense pleasure to receive
this award
thanks to icsc lumbar and cnbc tv 18
team
for recognizing us with india risk
management award
i would like to thank jury members for
evaluating
our efforts in the healthcare i.t
industry
working from upcoming city called
kolhapur
serving 1500 and plus hospitals from pan
india and 11 countries from global
i would like to share this platform will
definitely help
to create more awareness about risk
management techniques
in the business environment
[Applause]
risk management has become a top of mind
issue for boards
around the world nowhere more than in
pharmaceutical companies
up next the award for masters of risk in
pharma
and healthcare in the mid cap category
and the winner of this category is
dr lal path labs limited
it's great to receive this award in the
master of risk
farm and healthcare category in last
year was very difficult for everyone
including us and lot more has changed
with customer preference
or demand or way of working and
receiving this
award under risk management categories
is a great feeling
i think this will further boost our
company dr lal patlab to grow further
when it comes to the agriculture sector
and food security risk management needs
to serve
as a pillar in india our next award this
evening
is masters of risk in agriculture
in the mid cap category
and the award goes to
calvary seeds company limited but the
kaveri seed company based at hyderabad
is uh i mean we are honored to get this
you know
india risk management award and it means
a lot for the company
as you know it's helped us in improving
our i mean
furthermore in our endeavor to serve the
forming nation forming countries
forming farmers and you know we thank
the cnbc and tb 18 and
ica lombard for giving him this award
for recovery received company
[Applause]
the next category is masters of risk in
other sectors in the mid cap segment
a big congratulations to
acumen today private limited yeah on
behalf of
acumen today family accommodated
employees i take this honor and
privilege
to accept the honor of
india risk management awards by cnbc tv
18 and icici lombard we have been
the awardee for the first time and we
are very happy about
the recognition that we have got
the second last award for the evening is
a special jury citation for risk
management
in the mid cap category
and the winner of this award is
slate and sons thank you so much cnbc tv
icc lombard for recognizing our company
state and since we are grateful
and this means a lot to me it us to
further
make our company stronger and grow
more and more
[Applause]
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen it is now time to
announce the final award of the evening
and the final category
of the night masters of risk mid cap
company
of the year
and the winner of this category is
dr lao path labs limited it's
great to receive uh this award under
master of risk mid cap company of the
year
i would like to thank all the jury
members cnbc tv 18
and icici lamborgh it is the reflection
of our
entire team working at dr larpath labs
we have not only created
no value for all the stakeholders with
our customer patients
and all the investors but provided
reliable affordable and high quality
services to our customers and patients
[Music]
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age
risk management practitioners
[Music]
focus innovate
enable